Inventory of the Edward L. Munson papers, 1773-1972 (bulk 1947-1967)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Edward L. Munson papers
1773-1972
1947-1967
Munson, Edward L. (Edward Lyman), 1904-1967.
05526
20.44 cubic feet (37 boxes) + 14 other.
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Biography of Edward L. Munson
Edward Lyman Munson (1904-1967) organized and operated the Army Research branch of the War Department (1941-1942), organized and operated the Army Information Division, and was chief of the Army Pictorial Service. Following his retirement from the military, he was director of the NBC Film Division, an executive in the motion picture industry, and director of Television Operations of NBC Television.
Scope and Content
The Edward L. Munson papers contain biographical information, awards and citations, articles by Edward L. Munson, books concerning the military and war, and correspondence (1947-1967). Flags, decorations and other memorabilia are included. The collection contains more than 400 war posters, pen and ink etchings, and other drawings and notebooks. The collection also contains photographs and albums depicting those prominent in the military, as well as friends and family of Edward L. Munson. Motion pictures found in the collection include: "A Star is Born," "Appointment in Tokyo," "General MacArthur," "Here is Germany," "Know Your Allies Britain," "Know Your Enemy Japan," "The Negro Soldier," and "Why We Fight" training films. The collection also contains phonograph records of the Armed Forces Radio Service Basic Musical Library, Yank Swing Lesson, Series H. Programs, and other music. Also included in the collection are general order documents, deeds, programs for award ceremonies, and reports concerning the war department, military, television film, producers reports, 20th Century Fox Film Corporation, television network, and personal reports.
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
There are no known other archival collections created by Edward L. Munson at the date of processing.
Additional Information
Partial finding aid available in repository.
Acquisition Information
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of select material from this collection are available at https://digitalcollections.uwyo.edu/luna/servlet/uwydbuwy~198~198.
Access Terms
Motion picture producers and directors -- United States -- 20th century.; Television producers and directors -- United States -- 20th century.; Military history -- United States -- 20th century.; War posters, American.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Propaganda.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Propaganda.
Politics, Government, and Law; Military; Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Performing Arts
- Container List (PDF)
  The American Heritage Center is in the process of converting its older container lists to a more accessible format. This link is to an older version of a container list.
  - Link to Container List (PDF)
- World War I posters
  Select posters have been digitized and made available online. For a full listing of all posters please see link to the Container List.
  - Second Liberty Loan, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 6)
  - Third Liberty Loan, 1917 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 7)
  - Fourth Liberty Loan, 1917-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 8)
  - Victory Liberty Loan, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 9)
  - US Food Administration, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 11)
  - War Savings Stamps, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 12)
  - US Navy 1, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 13)
  - US Navy 2, 1917 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 14)
  - Marines 2, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 16)
  - Venereal Disease Campaign, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 18)
  - YWCA, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 20)
  - YMCA, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 21)
  - War Work Campaign, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous War Activities and Posters 2, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 25)
  - US Army, 1917-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 27)
  - US Army Corps: Tanks, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 37)
  - American Red Cross, 1914-1920 (Box Map Drawer, Folder 39)
- World War II posters
  - ...we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain..., 1939-1945 (Box Map Drawer)
  - Rationing means a fair share for all of us, 1939-1945 (Box Map Drawer)
  - Group Services Bulletin, 1939-1945 (Box Map Drawer)